

ENGINEERING LEADER

Details

Toronto, Canada +1 (519) 722-6504 <u>druska@gmail.com</u>

Links

GitHub

Stack Overflow

LinkedIn

Skills

Languages: Python, Java, Scala, Go, TypeScript, JavaScript

Infrastructure: Kubernetes, Docker, AWS, Azure

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, InfluxDB

Other: RabbitMQ, React, Websockets, Django

Profile

Proven engineering leader with 8 years of experience spanning across a variety of industries including Artificial Intelligence, Financial Services, and Education. With a keen focus on technical excellence, I have led and collaborated with cross functional teams in delivering reliable applications at scale.

Employment History

Engineering Manager, Ada Support Inc., Toronto

MARCH 2020 - PRESENT

- Managed a team of 10 to launch Ada's largest enterprise client to date, Zoom, to scale to over 100 times traffic, Achieved over 1 million page views per minute with low latency.
- Managed day-to-day customer demands on the engineering team, which increased customer satisfaction scores

Team Lead, Ada Support Inc., Toronto

APRIL 2020 - MARCH 2020

- Technical lead for a team of 2 developers
- Developed a new add-on for Ada, which was a realtime web app for customer service agents
- Delivered the product within 4 months

Software Architect, Ada Support Inc., Toronto

FEBRUARY 2020 - APRIL 2020

• Helped double Ada's engineering team from 15-30 in 6 months

Senior Team Lead, BigTerminal.com Inc., Toronto

NOVEMBER 2017 - JANUARY 2019

- Was the tech lead for a small company of 5 senior developers
- Was responsible for assessing what we should build with input from the CEO, and splitting across our team
- Traded the hedge fund's cryptocurrency via market bots, yielding up to 50% return on investment annually

Senior Team Lead, Coti Ltd., Toronto

JULY 2017 - DECEMBER 2017

- Technical and people lead for a team of 3
- Created a P2P instant payment platform on top of Ethereum
- Created the backend & frontend for this platform, including the ability to manage funds via credit card, Bitcoin, or Ethereum

Engineering Manager, Top Hat, Toronto

JANUARY 2017 - JULY 2017

- Technical & people lead for an iOS and Android team with 6 developers total
- Managed a remote Android team to increase engineering capacity
- Created a hack-resistant attendance using P2P Bluetooth tech in classrooms which shipped to customers in 4 months

Team Lead, Top Hat, Toronto

AUGUST 2014 - JANUARY 2017

- Was the technical and people lead of a team of 7 developers
- Helped scale Top Hat from 15-50 developers in 3 years
- Re-built Top Hat's frontend from Backbone to React in 6 months, while also reimagining the entire UX
- Create design patterns for all teams around standardizing REST API development, frontend web development

Full Stack Engineer, Top Hat, Toronto

MAY 2014 - AUGUST 2014

Co-Founder and CTO, BigTerminal.com Inc., Toronto

AUGUST 2013 - MAY 2014

- Worked as the technical lead with a business partner
- Successfully launched a financial web app which was a competitor to a Bloomberg terminal: BigTerminal.com
- Had an offer to be acqui-hired by a well known investor in the fintech space

Frontend Developer, Gold.net LLC, Toronto

DECEMBER 2012 - AUGUST 2013

- Was responsible for a web-based charting application. When the user panned and zoomed around the chart new data would be loaded automatically. This behaved similar to Google Maps, but for time-series data.
- Created embeddable charts that could be plugged into any website

Education

Bachelor of Science (BSc), Computer Science, Wilfrid Laurier University, Waterloo

SEPTEMBER 2008 - MAY 2012